Today we are making a backpack that would be appropriate for a child or a adult.
But you may want to consider exactly who this project would be made for before you go buy your supplies.
Some of the supplies that you may want to think about when you are looking for your fabric would be trim if it is going to be for a child.
You may want to think about something like ricrac.
For an adult, you may want to think about using a contrasting fabric.
But a different color fabric for the front and for the back that would give a little bit of contrast if it was for someone beside a child or even for a child.
The other things that we want to make sure that you have would be scissors, pins especially when you are cutting out your fabric cord cause if we make it in the same style of this bag that I was using for a guide cord is what is used to cinch the back up at the top.
Instead of grommets at the bottom, we would be using these D rings and we would make a loop at the bottom to loop the chord through.
You would also need your sewing machine of course.
Matching thread, a tape measure, and any other trim or applicate items that you may want to put on for decoration on your backpack.
Those are the main things that you would need for your backpack before you get started.
You may want to be sure that you have them assemble so you don't have to take a break and stop and run to the store in the middle of your project.
Probably most of the things that is needed has been mentioned here and that should take care of it for our project that we are doing today.